A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Policy Office, Records, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- III. Legislative Files, 2006-2009 (accession 44701)., Extent: 33.60 cubic feet (96 boxes). (Box 49-141, 170-172)
  - 2007 Regular Session
    - House of Delegates
      - HB 2569 (07) Tolling of speedy trial statute; law already in place during pendency by State is extended (Box 80, Folder 26)
      - HB 2570 (07) Victims of crime; right to nondisclosure of certain information (Box 80, Folder 27)
      - HB 2576 (07) Protective orders; extension by court (Box 80, Folder 28)
      - HB 2579 (07) Mechanic's lien; adds certification of mailing therefor by general contractor (Box 80, Folder 29)
      - HB 2580 (07) Mechanic's liens; certification of mailing for certain contractors (Box 80, Folder 30)
      - HB 2591 (07) Sexual offenses; notify defendant prior to punishment for subsequent offenses (Box 80, Folder 31)
      - HB 2594 (07) Driver's license; removes certain provision for suspension thereof (Box 80, Folder 32)
      - HB 2595 (07) Professional and Occupational Regulation, Department of; changes membership of Fair Housing Board (Box 80, Folder 33)
      - HB 2601 (07) Veterans Day; Board of Education to provide information for commemoration thereof (Box 80, Folder 34)
      - HB 2602 (07) Voluntary contributions of tax refunds; adds public library foundations, etc to list (Box 80, Folder 35)
      - HB 2603 (07) Foreign stock and nonstock corporations; annual registration and filing fees (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - HB 2614 (07) Electrical utility facilities; review of construction applications by State Corporation Commission (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - HB 2616 (07) Airports, private-use; those licensed not required to provide proof of financial responsibility (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - HB 2617 (07) Aircraft; proof of financial responsibility with respect thereto (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - HB 2624 (07) Government Performance and Results Act; each agency to report progress addressing impact of aging (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - HB 2625 (07) Prisoners; create system for identifying prisoners with learning disabilities (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - HB 2626 (07) Racing Commission; to adopt regulations concerning advance deposit account wagering, etc. (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - HB 2627 (07) Correctional Education, Department of; literacy program (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - HB 2628 (07) Correctional Education, Board of; composition of membership (Box 81, Folder 9)
      - HB 2631 (07) Student records; limitations on access thereto (Box 81, Folder 10)
      - HB 2637 (07) Alcoholic beverage control; creates limited mixed beverage restaurant licenses (Box 81, Folder 11)
      - HB 2638 (07) Alcoholic beverage control; clarifies outdoor dining areas for mixed beverage restaurant license (Box 81, Folder 12)
      - HB 2640 (07) Inoperable vehicles; prohibits imposition of local vehicle license taxes and fees thereon (Box 81, Folder 13)
      - HB 2642 (07) Subaqueous land; Marine Resources Commission to convey certain S and S Marine Supply in Hampton (Box 81, Folder 14)
      - HB 2645 (07) Charter; City of Suffolk (Box 81, Folder 15)
      - HB 2646 (07) Emergency protective orders; issuance thereof and judge to provide protected person with forms, etc. (Box 81, Folder 16)
      - HB 2649 (07) Pharmacy, Board of; grounds for discipline (Box 81, Folder 17)
      - HB 2653 (07) Firearms; illegal conveyance (Box 81, Folder 18)
      - HB 2654 (07) Military Affairs, Department of; establishes specific duties and functions to be carried out (Box 81, Folder 19)
      - HB 2659 (07) Writ on judgment; sheriff to post copy thereof to recover specific property on party' door (Box 81, Folder 20)
      - HB 2660 (07) Juveniles; investigation of social history prior to commitment (Box 81, Folder 21)
      - HB 2669 (07) Freedom of Information Act; allows public bodies to meet by electronic communication without quorum (Box 81, Folder 22)
      - HB 2671 (07) Sexually violent predators; civil commitment (Box 81, Folder 23)
      - HB 2673 (07) Jury sentencing; empanelment of new jury in event of deadlock (Box 81, Folder 24)
      - HB 2674 (07) Toy vehicles; prohibits use thereof on highways, exception (Box 81, Folder 25)
      - HB 2676 (07) Budgets, local; modifies existing requirements for advertising, etc. when a locality amends (Box 81, Folder 26)
      - HB 2678 (07) Opiate addiction treatment; centers to refrain from providing services on Sunday, exception (Box 81, Folder 27)
      - HB 2684 (07) Revised Uniform Anatomical Gift Act (UAGA); replaces current provisions in the code with this act (Box 81, Folder 28)
      - HB 2690 (07) Virginia Military Advisory Council; adds Secretary of Public Safety to membership, report (Box 81, Folder 29)
      - HB 2691 (07) Environmental Health Education and Training Fund; created (Box 81, Folder 30)
      - HB 2692 (07) Onsite Sewage Indemnification Fund; limitations (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - HB 2694 (07) Resources Authority; expands projects that can be financed to include land conservation and preservation (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - HB 2695 (07) Dams, low-head; owners to use signs, etc. to warn public of hazards of swimming, etc. posed thereby (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - HB 2707 (07) Electronic voting equipment; requirements and recount procedures (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - HB 2708 (07) Net energy metering; purchase of excess electricity generated by eligible customer-generator (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - HB 2710 (07) Dams and related facilities; service districts to construct, maintain, and operate (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - HB 2714 (07) Shooting enclosures, illegal; increases penalty for violating provisions thereof (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - HB 2720 (07) Charter; Town of Cheriton (Box 82, Folder 8)
      - HB 2723 (07) Communications sales and use tax; exemptions include military base customers (Box 82, Folder 9)
      - HB 2724 (07) Retail Sales and Use Tax; exemptions include certain property purchased by churches (Box 82, Folder 10)
      - HB 2726 (07) Emergency plans; review of certain by localities (Box 82, Folder 11)
      - HB 2727 (07) Condominium Act; allows elderly or disabled tenants in conversion units to assign purchase right (Box 82, Folder 12)
      - HB 2729 (07) FEMA Special Flood Hazard Area map; notification of changes thereto (Box 82, Folder 13)
      - HB 2730 (07) Hospital regulations; provision allowing patients to receive visits from whom they desire (Box 82, Folder 14)
      - HB 2732 (07) Brain and spinal cord injury registry; specifies conditions thereof (Box 82, Folder 15)
      - HB 2735 (07) National Association of Counties; locality to participate (Box 82, Folder 16)
      - HB 2738 (07) Minimum Wage Act; repeals exclusion for persons who are 65 thereunder (Box 82, Folder 17)
      - HB 2740 (07) Campaign finance disclosure; reports of independent expenditures by political action committees (Box 82, Folder 18)
      - HB 2749 (07) Sex offender registration; offender to include any electronic mail address, etc. that he will use (Box 82, Folder 19)
      - HB 2750 (07) Capital murder; premeditated killing of a judge or justice (Box 82, Folder 20)
      - HB 2752 (07) Amber Alert Program; use of certain technology (Box 82, Folder 21)
      - HB 2757 (07) Contractors, Board for; exemptions for certain career and technical education projects (Box 82, Folder 22)
      - HB 2758 (07) Freedom of Information Act; posting of meeting notices and minutes of public bodies (Box 82, Folder 23)
      - HB 2759 (07) Search warrant affidavits; delivery in person or by mail (Box 82, Folder 24)
      - HB 2765 (07) Construction; slayer statute (Box 82, Folder 25)
      - HB 2766 (07) Retirement benefits; exemption of certain from creditor process (Box 82, Folder 26)
      - HB 2772 (07) Fraudulent credit card application; false statements to obtain property or credit (Box 82, Folder 27)
      - HB 2776 (07) Sex offender treatment offices; prohibited in certain residential areas (Box 82, Folder 28)
      - HB 2780 (07) House of Delegates districts; technical adjustment in boundary line within King William County (Box 82, Folder 29)
      - HB 2781 (07) Transfer of highways, etc.; may transfer interest in or control over certain highways, etc. (Box 82, Folder 30)
      - HB 2782 (07) Bottomlands; conveyance of state-owned (Box 82, Folder 31)
      - HB 2783 (07) Child labor offenses; civil penalty that may be assessed (Box 82, Folder 32)
      - HB 2785 (07) Highway funds; additional allocation to certain port cities (Box 82, Folder 33)
      - HB 2786 (07) Retail Franchising Act; requirement of SCC for franchise registration (Box 82, Folder 34)
      - HB 2787 (07) License plates, special; issuance to members of U.S. Coast Guard (Box 82, Folder 35)
      - HB 2788 (07) Lieu of posting bond; adds surety bonds, etc. from attorney's escrow account to type of payment (Box 82, Folder 36)
      - HB 2789 (07) Uniform Statewide Building Code; violations, penalty (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - HB 2791 (07) Onsite sewage disposal system; permit for installing in certain counties (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - HB 2793 (07) Display of local license, decals, etc.; exempts certain public service companies therefrom (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - HB 2799 (07) Electric power and energy; purchase by Virginia Tech and municipal corporation (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - HB 2800 (07) Region 2000 Airport Authority Act; created (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - HB 2802 (07) Land application of sewage sludge; regulation and management thereof (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - HB 2809 (07) National Guard; employment protection (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - HB 2816 (07) Weights and measures; allows Commissioner to establish a schedule for examination thereof (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - HB 2818 (07) Polling place; allows no more than three representatives of each candidate to remain therein (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - HB 2825 (07) Land Conservation Fund; disbursement of moneys (Box 83, Folder 10)
      - HB 2829 (07) Doctrine of worthier title; abolished (Box 83, Folder 11)
      - HB 2830 (07) Divorce; revocation of death benefits, federal preemption (Box 83, Folder 12)
      - HB 2831 (07) Transfers to minors act; enables custodian of trust to transfer property without a court order (Box 83, Folder 13)
      - HB 2832 (07) Spendthrift trust; related duties (Box 83, Folder 14)
      - HB 2833 (07) Augmented estate; inclusion of insurance policies (Box 83, Folder 15)
      - HB 2834 (07) Home ownership grants; amount localities may provide for certain local government employees (Box 83, Folder 16)
      - HB 2835 (07) Attorney General; compromise and settlement of disputes (Box 83, Folder 17)
      - HB 2836 (07) Revocable trusts; validity thereof (Box 83, Folder 18)
      - HB 2837 (07) George Washington's birthday; Department of Education to provide schools information thereon (Box 83, Folder 19)
      - HB 2838 (07) Transportation infrastructure; VDOT to submit biennial report on maintenance and operation thereof (Box 83, Folder 20)
      - HB 2839 (07) Soil Scientists and Wetland Professionals, Board for; extends waiver of requirements, etc. (Box 83, Folder 21)
      - HB 2840 (07) Personnel Act; hiring preference for veterans for employment with State (Box 83, Folder 22)
      - HB 2845 (07) Emergency preparedness; makes several revisions related to orders of isolation and quarantine (Box 83, Folder 23)
      - HB 2850 (07) Intermodal Planning and Investment, Office of; change of name, and additional duties of Office (Box 83, Folder 24)
      - HB 2852 (07) Campaign finance disclosure; special registration provisions for certain committees (Box 83, Folder 25)
      - HB 2853 (07) Stun weapons; eliminates references to tasers throughout Code (Box 83, Folder 26)
      - HB 2854 (07) Transportation Board; Commissioner to report on various expenditures (Box 83, Folder 27)
      - HB 2855 (07) Search warrants; allows an agent of U. S. Department of Homeland Security, etc. (Box 83, Folder 28)
      - HB 2858 (07) Local community-based probation services; makes numerous technical changes throughout the Code (Box 83, Folder 29)
      - HB 2861 (07) Condominium and Property Owners' Association Acts; notice of meetings and technical amendments (Box 83, Folder 30)
      - HB 2864 (07) Powers of attorney; duties and liabilities of agents (Box 83, Folder 31)
      - HB 2880 (07) Health Research Fund; investment of moneys therein would be governed by certain provisions (Box 83, Folder 32)
      - HB 2882 (07) Southwest Virginia Health Facilities Authority; created (Box 83, Folder 33)
      - HB 2885 (07) Housing authorities; compensation of commissioners (Box 83, Folder 34)
      - HB 2890 (07) Secure juvenile facility or detention home; punishment for certain offenses committed within (Box 83, Folder 35)
      - HB 2893 (07) Student information; public schools and public institutions of higher education may retain copies (Box 83, Folder 36)
      - HB 2894 (07) St. Paul, Town of; allows industrial development authority to reduce number of board of directors (Box 83, Folder 37)
      - HB 2906 (07) Community Action Act; revises process for designation of community action agency (Box 83, Folder 38)
      - HB 2917 (07) Weight limits for gravel trucks; extends sunset provision (Box 83, Folder 39)
      - HB 2920 (07) Income tax, personal and corporate; statute of limitations for abuse tax avoidance transactions (Box 83, Folder 40)
      - HB 2923 (07) Human Trafficking, Commission On Prevention of; created, report (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - HB 2928 (07) Population brackets; replaces other descriptions found in Code of Virginia with locality names (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - HB 2946 (07) Electronics disposal and recycling; policies thereof are consistent with data, etc. policies (Box 84, Folder 3)
      - HB 2951 (07) Tolls; VDOT to impose and collect for use of Route 17 in City of Chesapeake (Box 84, Folder 4)
      - HB 2953 (07) Administrative subpoena; issued for records of electronic communication service, etc. (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - HB 2954 (07) Eminent domain; definition of public uses and limitations thereon (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - HB 2955 (07) Temporary detention orders; licensed physician to complete in-person evaluation (Box 84, Folder 7)
      - HB 2959 (07) Police and court records; expungement hearing to occur if person granted writ vacating a conviction (Box 84, Folder 8)
      - HB 2962 (07) Life-sharing communities; defines and establishes criteria for licensing and inspection thereof (Box 84, Folder 9)
      - HB 2968 (07) Child pornography cases; venue (Box 84, Folder 10)
      - HB 2969 (07) Medical students; prohibition of unauthorized pelvic exams (Box 84, Folder 11)
      - HB 2975 (07) Personal Property Tax Relief Act of 1998; commissioner of revenue to rely upon DMV information (Box 84, Folder 12)
      - HB 2978 (07) Watercraft; maiming of another resulting from operating thereof while intoxicated (Box 84, Folder 13)
      - HB 2980 (07) Child pornography; seizure and forfeiture of equipment (Box 84, Folder 14)
      - HB 2981 (07) Criminal charges; effect of dismissal (Box 84, Folder 15)
      - HB 2982 (07) Special counsel; compensation thereof (Box 84, Folder 16)
      - HB 2989 (07) Portsmouth Port and Industrial Commission; authority to provide financing by leasing, etc. facilities (Box 84, Folder 17)
      - HB 2990 (07) Subaqueous lands; Marine Resources Commission to convey adjoining parcels thereof (Box 84, Folder 18)
      - HB 2991 (07) Public defenders; duties (Box 84, Folder 19)
      - HB 2994 (07) Dental hygienists; authority to administer topical oral fluorides (Box 84, Folder 20)
      - HB 3002 (07) Affordable housing; investment of funds (Box 84, Folder 21)
      - HB 3005 (07) Natural gas pipeline; Marine Resources Commission to grant easements and rights-of-way (Box 84, Folder 22)
      - HB 3007 (07) Juvenile certification; only certified upon conviction (Box 84, Folder 23)
      - HB 3008 (07) Uniform crime reports; shall be distributed in an electronic format (Box 84, Folder 24)
      - HB 3011 (07) Bonding requirements; facilities dedicated for public use (Box 84, Folder 25)
      - HB 3015 (07) Military Family Relief Fund; assistance after active duty (Box 84, Folder 26)
      - HB 3016 (07) Insurance agents; repeals a provision for license termination (Box 84, Folder 27)
      - HB 3017 (07) Youth Internet Safety Fund; created (Box 84, Folder 28)
      - HB 3018 (07) Old Dominion University; certain undergraduate classes offered at Virginia Beach Higher Education Center (Box 84, Folder 29)
      - HB 3019 (07) Charter; City of Bristol (Box 84, Folder 30)
      - HB 3021 (07) Benefits consortium; created for private institutions of higher education (Box 84, Folder 31)
      - HB 3022 (07) Income tax, state; filing threshold amounts, personal exemptions therefor (Box 84, Folder 32)
      - HB 3023 (07) Drug test; use of synthetic urine to defeat (Box 84, Folder 33)
      - HB 3024 (07) Speed limits; analysis of accident and law-enforcement data required before increasing (Box 84, Folder 34)
      - HB 3025 (07) Voter participation; Board of Elections to provide information thereof (Box 84, Folder 35)
      - HB 3028 (07) Driver's license, commercial; fee for failing to attend scheduled skills test appointment (Box 84, Folder 36)
      - HB 3031 (07) Comprehensive plans; affect of approval of transmission lines (Box 84, Folder 37)
      - HB 3034 (07) DNA analysis; probation officer shall review Local Inmate Data System and report identity of offender (Box 84, Folder 38)
      - HB 3037 (07) Potomac River Fisheries Commission; powers and duties (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - HB 3039 (07) Water and sewer charges; adds Town of Blacksburg to localities that may attach lien on real estate (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - HB 3041 (07) Conservators of peace; sworn municipal park rangers may be (Box 85, Folder 3)
      - HB 3043 (07) Health Commissioner; required to designate licensed physician to oversee minority health efforts (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - HB 3044 (07) Income tax, corporate; extends sunset provision for machinery and equipment used in recycling process (Box 85, Folder 5)
      - HB 3045 (07) Safety inspection stickers and vehicle inspections; required for parked vehicles (Box 85, Folder 6)
      - HB 3046 (07) Private roads as highways; governing body of any county, etc. may adopt ordinances designating (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - HB 3048 (07) Emergency management plans; local and interjurisdictional agency to review (Box 85, Folder 8)
      - HB 3055 (07) Casualty, burglary and theft insurances; policies to include certain provisions (Box 85, Folder 9)
      - HB 3061 (07) Health care practitioner; authority to send laboratory test results directly to patient (Box 85, Folder 10)
      - HB 3062 (07) Retail Sales and Use Tax; exemptions include nonprofit entities, audit requirements (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - HB 3064 (07) Suicidal students; higher educational institutions to develop policies to identify (Box 85, Folder 12)
      - HB 3068 (07) Electric utility service; advances scheduled expiration of capped rate period (part one) (Box 85, Folder 13)
      - HB 3068 (07) Electric utility service; advances scheduled expiration of capped rate period (part two) (Box 85, Folder 14)
      - HB 3071 (07) Odometer readings; exempts certain vehicles therefrom (Box 85, Folder 15)
      - HB 3075 (07) Wildlife Center; authorizes vehicles owned thereby to rescue or euthanize injured wildlife (Box 85, Folder 16)
      - HB 3076 (07) Virginia Covered Bridge Festival in Patrick County; designating as official state festival (Box 85, Folder 17)
      - HB 3078 (07) Charitable gaming; regulation of bingo callers (Box 85, Folder 18)
      - HB 3079 (07) Appalachian Region Interstate Compact and Commission; created (Box 85, Folder 19)
      - HB 3082 (07) Religious freedom; reiterates an individual's freedom of religion (Box 85, Folder 20)
      - HB 3083 (07) Liens; nonexoneration thereof against property bequeathed (Box 85, Folder 21)
      - HB 3084 (07) School bus warning devices; requires red lights to be activated whenever bus door is opened (Box 85, Folder 22)
      - HB 3085 (07) Children; expands scope of rape shield statute to include prosecution for taking indecent liberties (Box 85, Folder 23)
      - HB 3087 (07) Health spas; allows owner to transfer ownership of facility and all its contracts to new owner (Box 85, Folder 24)
      - HB 3090 (07) Privileged communications; physician peer review and physician accreditation entities (Box 85, Folder 25)
      - HB 3093 (07) Assessments; notice of change (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - HB 3094 (07) Virginia Coal Heritage Trail; designating as certain highway segments in Southwest Virginia (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - HB 3098 (07) Ignition interlock; installation in vehicle, and loss of restricted license (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - HB 3111 (07) Tobacco Settlement Foundation Endowment; created (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - HB 3112 (07) Notaries; fees for services (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - HB 3113 (07) Environmental Quality, Department of; consolidation of various boards, increase of authority (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - HB 3114 (07) Aerospace Advisory Council; created (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - HB 3117 (07) Criminal Justice Services Board; increases membership for Committee on Training (Box 86, Folder 8)
      - HB 3119 (07) Russell County Water and Sewer Authority; each member thereof to be customer of service provided (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - HB 3120 (07) Farm wineries; no county, city, or town shall adopt an ordinance prohibiting storage, etc. (Box 86, Folder 10)
      - HB 3122 (07) Driving without a license; enhanced penalty for persons convicted of second offense (Box 86, Folder 11)
      - HB 3123 (07) Housing authorities; must hold at least one public hearing to receive views of citizens (Box 86, Folder 12)
      - HB 3127 (07) Nonresident; when personal jurisdiction may be exercised (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - HB 3129 (07) Service districts; additional powers with regard to dredging of creeks and rivers (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - HB 3131 (07) Health and Human Resources, Secretary of; clarifies powers to implement long-term care policy (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - HB 3132 (07) Victims of crime; employers to allow leave to attend criminal proceedings (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - HB 3133 (07) Sanitary landfills; Department of Environmental Quality to develop postclosure guidelines (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - HB 3134 (07) Onsite sewage systems; Board of Health to establish program for operation and maintenance thereof (Box 86, Folder 18)
      - HB 3135 (07) State forests; designates proceeds generated to Counties of Appomattox, Buckingham, and Cumberland (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - HB 3137 (07) Health coverage; expedited review of appeals of final adverse decisions (Box 86, Folder 20)
      - HB 3138 (07) Department of Medical Assistance Services; recovery of third party liability payments (Box 86, Folder 21)
      - HB 3140 (07) Charitable Gaming, Department of; required to complete training to be registered bingo callers (Box 86, Folder 22)
      - HB 3141 (07) Local governing body tie breakers; eliminates use of an unelected person (Box 86, Folder 23)
      - HB 3143 (07) Motor vehicle license taxes and fees, local; restates limitation on amount (Box 86, Folder 24)
      - HB 3144 (07) Lettner, Kimberly S.; authorized to retain her service pistol and shotgun for service to State Police (Box 86, Folder 25)
      - HB 3151 (07) First Landing State Park; Department of Conservation to lease certain land therein (Box 86, Folder 26)
      - HB 3153 (07) Income tax, state; SCC to determine tax costs for investor-owned public utilities (Box 86, Folder 27)